Emmanuel (God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank you
We were shocked this morning when we saw many people around the church -
they came to me and said that there are people around the church with sickness and disease.
I said, "Wow, this is not a healing service".
It is a normal service.
But what we are seeing today -
I think we will not allow these people to go.
But next time...
SCOAN Sunday Service
Next time I think God would permit us to allow them to go.
Yes, that is the way God does.
He said before one is before all.
Don't do that again.
Yes, if you now do them...
Okay.
While praying for them, the grace is enough for you to receive: Put your demand on the anointing
While praying for them you do what? Put your demand on the anointing.
When I say, "In the name of Jesus", you say, "Oh, Lord Jesus, oh Lord".
While I pray for them, begin to pray for yourself
and when the person gets healed, you are healed.
When the person gets delivered, you are delivered.
Hallelujah.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let me usher you to that because we are about to enter another section.
It will be be difficult for me to begin to heal, pray for people and carry you along without ushering you there.
Ushering means teaching you, preparing you.
You need a proper connection to understand what we are about to do.
You just finished dancing. That realm of dancing - it takes anointing to dance.
I need to take you out of that, and take you to another realm.
So, I need to get you prepared.
Hallelujah.
Are you there?
We are going to another realm -
another realm where you will see things happen, but you won't know how they happened.
Another realm where physical hands will not be needed to do things.
You will see this happen - our strength, our tension are not necessary, are not needed -
another realm where our voice and our tongue are not needed.
When you want to move this, you need to use your hand.
But in this case, you don't need the hand to take it, and it will move.
That is why it is difficult for us to understand why something happens.
God does not give us what we know how to do.
He always gives us what we don't know how to do, so that he can teach us.
Look at this.
If God says, "Carry it", you know how to carry it. This is it.
No, what God normally does is to ask you to carry this pillar. Look at the pillar.
Can you carry it ? He always gives us what we don't know how to do,
what we cannot even do by ourselves.
Because he wants to teach us - in the process of teaching us, He gets us trained in His own way.
He gets us reformed in His own way.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you with me?
He does not just heal what a medical doctor can just treat you for.
If you are sick, you meet a doctor and he would treat you.
This is why I was saying:
If you cannot believe God with your tablets and your drugs,
you cannot believe Him without your tablets.
You carry a drug for hypertension, a drug for heart attack, a drug for diabetics.
You have it in your pocket because you must take it every two hours.
You are sitting down and begin to pray, "Lord, I don't want to use these drugs anymore. Heal me, heal me".
At the end of the day, you are prayed for.
After praying for you, you now begin to look for an evangelist,
"Please, I want to know whether I should still use my drugs.
I want to know whether I can still use my tablets.
I would need to see the man of God".
"Prophet, these are my tablets. I don't know what to do with it."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If you cannot believe God with your tablets and your drugs,
you cannot believe Him without your tablets and your drugs.
God has nothing against your tablets.
He has nothing against it - it is made from a natural plant.
The soap you are using, either a medicated or a different kind of soap -
those things are just like tablets. If using tablets is wrong, the soap you are using is also wrong.
The cream you are using to rub your body is wrong.
These are from plants, medicated things from the doctors and pharmacies.
If that drug is bad, your cream, your soap you are using every day are then also bad.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I was giving you some clues on how you would know that you are free
or that God does not want you to use your tablets again.
If you have been prayed for, there are some signs that actually remind you of your tablets:
either you would have a serious headache, feel dizzy or discomfort.
Your body would be trembling.
These are some of the signs that would normally remind you of your tablets.
But when you have been prayed for and suddenly, you don't have those signs again,
automatically, you will forget your drugs.
You just find that you live, sleep and eat.
On the second or third day, you ask yourself, "I have not been taking that drug, I've forgotten".
You have forgotten because those signs are gone. That is God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is God.
You have to forget because those signs are gone.
When those signs are gone - the signs of headache, unability to sleep, unability to eat, all kinds of signs -
you cannot sense them again, and those are the signs that remind you of your drug and tablets.
First, second day, you will just realise, "My dear, for the past two days, I have not been taking my drugs.
because those signs are gone".
That is God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
But when you keep on remembering your drugs after you have been prayed for,
something is wrong.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is it.
Many of you have been sitting here since this morning.
At home, they can't try to sit for five hours without taking a tablet.
But right now, they have forgotten about their tablet because they can't feel any sign.
That is God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let us quickly move ahead to our healing and deliverance section today.
Let's take a very short text in the Bible.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The book of John 1, verse 33:
"And I myself did not know him, but the one who sent me to baptise with water told me."
If you take it from verse 1, you would understand it better.
But I am taking it from verse 33.
I take it again:
"And I myself did not know him, but the one who sent me to baptise with water told me,
the man on whom you see the Spirit come down and remain..."
But today, it is like the Spirit comes down on us but does not remain.
The miracle happens to us but seems not to be permanent.
We keep receiving blessing but we cannot keep the blessing.
We keep receiving deliverance but after a while, you are possessed again.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Jesus wants to be Himself in us.
Are you with me?
He wants to be Himself in us.
MESSAGE TITLE: LET THE HOLY SPIRIT REMAIN
But because we keep on grieving Him, we are not allowing Him.
He does not remain permanent when we grieve Him.
He does not remain when He is grieved.
He does not remain.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We grieve Him by our pride and we express our pride in various ways.
Like this: "OK, those of you that received healing, come out".
When you are waiting for healing, you are crying, shouting, this and that.
Immediately you are healed, you don't want to come out.
You don't want to face the camera.
But when you were sick, you wanted to face the camera.
We express our pride in various ways.
Can you see some of the reasons why we cannot maintain...
It says that the Holy Spirit came down on Him and remained.
We receive but not remain.
After a while when we get out there...
There are many things we do.
You hold a grudge against your brother - you have already grieved the Holy Spirit.
After the healing, you still hold a grudge against your brother
and the Bible says,"'Forgive us as we forgive those who trespass against us".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You should not be surprised if the Bible is not real while reading, if you hold a grudge.
You will be reading the Bible, but it is not alive
because you are holding a grudge, offence against your brother.
That is one of the reasons why when you read the Bible, you are just wasting your time.
There is no life in what you are reading about.
There is book, there is life, coming together.
Scripture is literature but when it is inspired by the Holy Spirit, it becomes the Bible.
It is when it is inspired by the Holy Spirit, it has authority.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you hold grudges against a brother, you have already grieved the Holy Spirit.
You should not be surprised if the Bible is not real when reading.
This is why we men of God - sometimes, I just laugh.
Holding offence against ourselves and we stand on the pulpit and begin to preach.
The Bible cannot be real when holding an offence or you just finished accusing your fellow ministers of God,
"That place is not good" and on next Sunday, you hold the Bible and begin to preach.
What do you need to do now before we go into the realm of healing, deliverance and salvation?
You need to let go of your past.
Whether you are right or wrong, if you let go in your heart, it is OK.
Even without giving a phone call to whoever you are holding an offence against,
once you let go in your heart, it is finished.
You have settled with God.
Even if you don't give a phone call to the person you are holding an offence against,
but you decide in your heart to let go, you have settled with God.
When you sometimes say, "This woman - they should kill her", you don't know that maybe this woman has settled with God.
If you have killed the woman, and this woman had settled with God, you are committing an offence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Let go of offence
because Jesus wants to be Himself in us.
Tell your neighbour.
Jesus wants to be Himself in us.
The Holy Spirit wants to be Himself in us.
If He wants to be Himself in us, we need to allow Him to be Himself in us.
We need to do what?
Tell your neighbour:
You need to allow Him to be Himself in you.
By holding offence against your neighbour, the Holy Spirit cannot remain.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
All you need to know now is: How can the blessing remain?
That is what we call maintenance.
If you are healed, will you be able to maintain the healing?
If you are delivered, how will you maintain the deliverance?
If you are blessed, how will you maintain the blessing?
Your life is like this because you have not maintained them.
If you had been maintaining God's blessings in your life, your life would not look like this.
Many things God had given you, you failed to maintain them.
MESSAGE TITLE: LET THE HOLY SPIRIT REMAIN
Holding grudges against your brother - you have already grieved the Holy Spirit.
When you grieve the Holy Spirit, you will read the Bible but will not understand it.
It will not be alive - as if you are reading literature, as if you are reading a novel.
This is why you don't understand the Bible.
You take some psalms to read, you rehearse the psalms.
And you realise that... no!
Even the name Jesus you call, you are supposed to call it by authority -
but each time you call the name Jesus, you are calling yourself.
You say, "In Jesus' name" and you realise you are calling yourself because nobody answers you.
Only the people that are around you hear you, and you yourself hear yourself.
That is just it because you have grieved the Holy Spirit by holding offence, holding grudges.
Begin to release yourself right now.
You can make a decision now that enough is enough.
I have said it all. Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right...
Leave it for God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Begin right now; let me see your heart, your spirit in communion with God.
Begin to communicate; begin to pray right now.
Begin to pray and say, "Lord I surrender".
That is the first step in surrendering to God; say "I surrender".
If you have surrendered, have you let go of offence, pain of the past, bitterness?
At least something happened before you can have bitterness in your heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Resentment.
Hatred.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Right now, I want to see your spirit begin to commune with God, pray in your spirit.
Pray in your spirit.
Begin to settle your account right now, viewers at home, begin to settle your account.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank You, Lord. In Jesus' name.
Rise up. I surrender.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
All to Jesus I surrender, all to Him I freely give
I will ever love and trust Him in His presence daily
I surrender all
All to Thee my blessed Saviour I surrender all
That is the first step in relationship with God.
It has been very difficult for many of us; you keep claiming your rights.
I have been cheated.
This is an embarrassment.
He is the one to be saying sorry.
He cheated me.
No. Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right to hold an offence
or grudge against your brother.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Because it affects every area of your life.
You read the Bible, it will not come alive.
It is this heart that converts what you are reading.
You read and take it to the conversion room;
the conversion room will convert it and send it to the Holy Spirit.
Oh my God, I hope you quite understand what I am talking about.
Let me use the Bible as a good example of what I am talking about.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is my Bible.
I open my Bible, I would read: "The Lord would have compassion on Jacob".
What I have just read now, would be taken to the heart.
If it does not go to the heart, it is just mere literature, words.
I have read it now. For that Word to be real and to be alive, it needs to be taken to the heart.
The heart would now convert the Word. After converting the Word, it would send it the Holy Ghost.
The Holy Spirit would now be affecting it.
It would now become an instrument of healing, blessing, salvation and deliverance.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I hope you understand the word conversion.
It means to refine.
When you take gold, it needs to pass through the furnace for refining.
So also, the Word you are reading now, "The Lord would have compassion for Jacob".
This is the Word but it would go straight to the heart
and the heart would now refine it.
When the heart refines it, it would now join the Holy Spirit, the Spirit of God
and then, it becomes an instrument.
Heart means man's spirit.
But if your heart is holding grudges,
if your heart is holding pain,
if your heart is holding hatred, it would not go there.
Only one thing occupies the heart.
Once hatred is there, nothing can go there.
Unless your heart is clear, you have a free heart.
When you have that free spirit, there is no hatred in your heart,
you don't hold grudges, you don't have anything against anyone,
your heart is free, that means a free spirit.
Then, the Word can go there, be converted, join to the Spirit of the Father
and become an instrument to use.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What is in your heart? A lot.
Heart means man's spirit. What is in your spirit? A lot.
That is why this Word you are reading will continue to be literature - history about Jacob.
If my heart is not free, I am just reading about Jacob.
It is history about Jacob unless it is taken to the heart, the heart converts it, refines it
and joins it to the Spirit of the Father.
When He joins it to the Spirit of the Father,
it becomes an instrument of healing, deliverance and salvation.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ask yourself, "What is in my heart?" Your heart is full of the past.
People that have hurt you. People that have hated you. People that have cheated you.
People that have embarrassed you.
At a lot of the places you worked in the past, they refused to pay you.
You spent one year in a company and they refused to pay you this money. You will never forgive them.
If you want to know a true Christian. Just go near, when he is praying.
Through his prayer, you would know whether he is a Christian or not.
"Oh God, I rebuke him, I kill him.
God, I bulldoze him. I will not forgive him. In the name of Jesus."
You would know that this one is not a Christian.
That is when he would be vomiting the pain in his heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ask your neighbour:
What is in your heart?
Now you know the meaning of free heart.
Heart means man's spirit - a free spirit.
A free spirit is a heart that lets go of offence.
Once the heart lets go of offence, when you are reading your Bible,
it will go straight to your heart and your heart will refine it,
take it to the Holy Ghost, join them together and it will become an instrument.
But if your heart is not free from all this pain, people that have embarrassed you,
you can never see the Bible alive or real.
You continue to read your Bible as if you are reading James Hadley Chase - history.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The society has cheated you.
You are a professor, you have PhD, you are jobless.
The society has cheated you, that's another offence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are working under someone who has no certificate, and you have PhD.
And this person that has no certificate is your boss.
Anytime you see him and he calls you, "Come on. Give me that file",
you ask yourself, "Ah, I have PhD. This one is an illiterate".
You would still carry that file, with pain.
You would now carry the file.
"I know my name"
You carry the file.
"Put it here!"
"Yes, sir."
You now look at his neck...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
All the time you look at your boss who always instructs you.
The race is not always for the swiftest or fastest.
If you are better than your boss in every area of life -
stature, wisdom, understanding, education, human natural gifts -
you realise that you are better than him, and he is your boss -
don't forget that the race is not always for the swiftest.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God put you there to learn some lessons.
Your journey is not going to stop there.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You always talk as if your journey would end there.
What you are talking about is just one out of history in your life.
You would soon leave the place. You are going to encounter a lot and a lot.
If God is preparing you for greatness,
He would prepare you for that greatness.
How does God prepare people for greatness?
He would take you from stupid, through rustic people, illerate people;
he wants you to understand everything.
He will allow you to pass through all those foolish things.
So that when you get to that position, you would understand what it is to be a rustic boy.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
There are many heroes today that are not from God.
Not every hero or societal people are from God.
There are many that are not from God.
This is why God said, "The peace that I am giving you is not as the world gives".
It means the success I am giving you, is different from the one the world gives.
God himself declares that the world can give success,
but my own success is quite different from the one the world gives to its people.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If now you see someone in a high position, successful, you need to ask,
"Is this God's success or the world's success?"
Sometimes, if God is taking you to a high place, He would even allow you to work under the world's success.
He would allow you to work under criminals.
He would allow you to work under stupid people.
But He would protect you.
The little time He would allow you to work there, He would protect you.
Because He is preparing you for....
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is God.
You must have a degree in love and also in hatred.
So that when you occupy that position, you will be able to explain, you will be able to understand what it is,
what it means to go through hatred.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God always makes us fit for the position.
He makes us fit for it. He would train us.
You should be ready for God's training.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
So, once again.
Take this word: Our heart refines the Word in the Bible.